<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DVD Pila!</title>
    <description>This is the landing page for the DVD Pila! project.  DVD Pila! is a web application to help organize your DVD archives.</description>
    <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 05:43:10 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 05:43:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Responsiveness Procrastination?</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;dvdpila responsiveness screeny&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/dvdpila_responsive.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a previous &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/asommer70/blog/third-times-a-charm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned that the next step for DVD Pila! is to start marketing it.  Well that was going to be the next step until I started using the app and got very annoyed at some of the bugs I didn&#39;t realize were there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugs are fixed so it&#39;s time for the marketing right?  Not quite. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&#39;m procrastinating (it definitely feels like I&#39;m procrastinating), but instead of working on the marketing I&#39;ve been working on making the app responsive.  I&#39;d like to be able to use the site from my tablets and phones, but that wasn&#39;t really a major feature.  I think even with the HTML5 supported videos you have to use an third party apps to play them on Android and iOS.  I haven&#39;t done a lot of testing though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&#39;m scared of criticism if I post &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdpila.thehoick.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD Pila!&lt;/a&gt; to places like Reddit and Hacker News.  I guess I&#39;m just going to have to get over it and plow through.  Otherwise what&#39;s the point?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 05:08:36 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/06/responsiveness-procrastination%3F/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/06/responsiveness-procrastination%3F/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bugs Fixed Release Time</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;dvdpila 1.3 release&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/dvdpila_1.3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out I just needed one more day, and one more release to make &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdpila.thehoick.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD Pila!&lt;/a&gt; work the way I&#39;d like.  I needed to rearrange some elements in the templates, and add some &lt;em&gt;observers&lt;/em&gt; to get things rocking.  I did end up finding a couple of more bugs that were a pain while using the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that it&#39;s not enough to get a feature working and do a release.  You need to actually use the whole app and make sure that things work they way you expect.  Instead of immediately creating a new release.  This time I used the app for a few hours adding, editing DVDs, etc before setting up the release.  Definitely a wise decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m sure it&#39;s obvious, but actually using the app wasn&#39;t really on my list until this project.  I&#39;ve always tested my web apps, but in this case testing just didn&#39;t cut it.  I&#39;ve learned a lot building this project, and have had a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is the first project that I will actually use.  There have been a couple of things in the past that after I developed them I was all like pffttt.  Who cares...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the majority of my development efforts have been for other people... they do use the web apps I&#39;ve created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 09:08:41 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/05/bugs-fixed-release-time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/05/bugs-fixed-release-time/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More Bugs More Problems</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;bugs and bugs and bugs&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/bugs.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I had all the bugs fixed up for release.  Mostly that&#39;s true, but whenever I go to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdpila.thehoick.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD Pila!&lt;/a&gt; things don&#39;t work quite like I would expect them to.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple things like clicking on the logo icon from search results doesn&#39;t take you back to the main page with all the results.  Also, searching from inside a DVD page doesn&#39;t take you to the search results.  It does show you the results once you go back to the index page though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These little things make the web app annoying to use.  It&#39;s those little annoying things that add up and add up and compound and blast into your thinker... then you don&#39;t want to use the app ever again.  I think the main problem with people using this app is to get it installed on their system, so I want to make things work as rock solid as possible once/if they do get it up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short I&#39;m going to put off the &quot;marketing&quot; part of the project until I have all the little banjaxes worked out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 10:08:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/04/more-bugs-more-problems/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/04/more-bugs-more-problems/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Third Times A Charm</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;dvdpila marketing fun&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/dvdpila_marketing.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Made a new release of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdpila.thehoick.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD Pila!&lt;/a&gt;.  Version 1.2 should now work as expected.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tidied up some of the display CSS as well to make each &quot;dvd block&quot; have the same height and width.  This makes things look a  lot better.  Things just look better when they are in neat little rows.  I haven&#39;t tested the latest release in my &lt;em&gt;production&lt;/em&gt; setup yet as we are travelling this weekend.  Hopefully I won&#39;t have to release version 1.3 until some time in the future.  At least a couple of months from now would be nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think for the month of July I&#39;m going to do as little development on DVD Pila! as possible.  Instead of cranking out more code/features I&#39;m going to learn as much as I can about marketing a software product. I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Growth-Hacker-Marketing-Advertising-Portfolio-ebook/dp/B00BPDR3JM&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;&quot;Growth Hacker Marketing&quot;&lt;/a&gt; a few weeks ago and really loved it.  It&#39;s a great place to start getting the word out about your product.  Of course the main advise in growth hacking is to start marketing before you build anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing the marketing first helps you arrive at Product Market Fit, which means you actually make something people want.  In the case of DVD Pila! I was totally scratching my own itch.  If people don&#39;t want it no big deal.  It does what I set out to do when starting the project, and I learned a lot about Flask and Ember.js.  Learning was the real goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder if I should start a &lt;em&gt;Daily Marketing Blog&lt;/em&gt;?  Maybe on Linkedin...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 16:08:58 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/03/third-times-a-charm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/03/third-times-a-charm/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 1.0 Release That Wasn&#39;t</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;dvd pila release screeny&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/dvdpila_release.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so excited the other day to release a 1.0 version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdpila.thehoick.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD Pila!&lt;/a&gt;, but maybe I should have taken some time and calmed down.  After generating the release in Github I worked on the documentation in the wiki for installing DVD Pila! in a &quot;production&quot; environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked up how to deploy a &lt;a href=&quot;http://flask.pocoo.org/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt; web app into a production environment.  Figured that is what most people who want to run DVD Pila!, if there are any people who want to run it, will do.  I settled on using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tornadoweb.org/en/stable/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Tornado&lt;/a&gt; for running my own production installation, and started documenting that.  After installing Tornado and cloning the repo into an Ubuntu LXC container, I realized that there were some additional files needed as well as some configuration options that I didn&#39;t commit into the sample config file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So virtually right after &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/asommer70/dvdpila/releases&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;releasing 1.0&lt;/a&gt; I had to release 1.1.  Woo more version numbers, heh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually there was a pretty big bug with adding new DVD entries in the released versions that I just fixed.  If the server wasn&#39;t able to find from &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Duck Duck Go&lt;/a&gt; information on the title entered in the web form, then it would boilk and not create the new entry in the database.  Some additional Python code to handle an AttributeError exception solved it, but I have yet to generate a new release containing the fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wonder if Github will let you redo a release...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 14:08:54 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/02/the-1.0-release-that-wasn't/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/02/the-1.0-release-that-wasn't/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HTML5 Video Position Saving</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;playback code screeny&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/playback_code.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last feature I wanted to land for &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdpila.thehoick.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD Pila!&lt;/a&gt; 1.0 is saving where in a video a user left off, and be able to start from where they left off once they play the video again.  Turns out implimenting this isn&#39;t all that hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accomplish this wonderous feat of development awesomeness, I first had to add a column to the single grand table.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.3/static/sql-altertable.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL documentation&lt;/a&gt; helped to blast a numeric &lt;em&gt;playback_time&lt;/em&gt; field into the table.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Guide/HTML/Using_HTML5_audio_and_video&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;MDN&lt;/a&gt; is a great page detailing the video, and audio, element.  There I learned all about the JavaScript &lt;em&gt;play&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;pause&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;seek&lt;/em&gt; methods.  I figured it&#39;d be easy to integrate them into Ember.js.  Well maybe not easy, but it should be doable.  I wasn&#39;t able to find a guide, blog post, etc on using HTML5 video with Ember, but I did find &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/11416776/how-to-display-time-of-video-in-ember-js-handlebars&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; Stackoverflow post that is pretty close to what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a some experimentation, I had the feature working the way I&#39;d like.  With that DVD PIla! is ready for 1.0 in my esteemed estimation.  There are a few things that still need fixed up, and I wanted to look at comments for the blog, but I&#39;ll probably come back to that stuff down the road sometime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 07:08:12 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/01/html5-video-position-saving/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/08/01/html5-video-position-saving/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Search and Pagination Success!</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;search and pagination ftw!&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/search_or_pagination_win.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out the easiest way to fix my Ember.js pagination and search problem is to move the search functionality into it&#39;s own controller, move the search field out of the DVD list div, and apply some if statements in the template to display either search results or the paginated &lt;em&gt;all DVDs&lt;/em&gt; list.  Took a lot of learning to figure that out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might add some pagination to the search results at some point, but for now I&#39;m just glad it&#39;s working the way it is.  I&#39;m sure there&#39;s better ways to do search than a PostgreSQL regex as well.  Though I was doing a JavaScript regex before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://alg.github.io/talks/emberjs&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;This cool&lt;/a&gt; Ember demo wasn&#39;t 100% responsible for the solution, but I borrowed a lot of code from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alg&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Aleksey&lt;/a&gt;.  I also learned about the &lt;em&gt;insertNewline&lt;/em&gt; method which I know will come in handy in either this project or future ones.  Learning more about Ember ArrayControllers and attribute bindings was helpful too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I can see the 1.0 release of DVD Pila! and it feels good...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 05:07:56 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/31/search-and-pagination-success/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/31/search-and-pagination-success/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pagination or Search</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;to search or not to search&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/search_or_pagination.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally had a chance to get back to my Ember.js project today.  Still bashing my head against the error I get when adding a record to the paginated collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve tried removing all the custom code I&#39;ve found around the web.  I removed the star rating, moved the &quot;add new DVD&quot; functionality into it&#39;s own page instead of including it as a hidden form on the main page, and also removed all the pagination code and double checked that things worked without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&#39;t until I removed the search functionality wich sets the controller &lt;em&gt;arrangedContent&lt;/em&gt; attribute, and tried adding a new record that I made another step forward.  If both pagination and search are implemented things go bonkers when adding a record.  Disable one or the other and things work just fine and dandy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The angle I&#39;m working on to solve this little pickle is to move the search to the server using some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.3/static/functions-matching.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL pattern matching&lt;/a&gt; and send back the results via JSON.  This should allow me to move the search field into the navigation menu instead of having it at the top of the main content area.  If I can get it working I think it&#39;ll be pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 11:07:42 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/29/pagination-or-search/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/29/pagination-or-search/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Problems with Pagination and Ember</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;pages&quot; class=&quot;post-image&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/pages.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve blasted into a problem with adding DVD records to the ArrayController in Ember.js.  The pagination guide I followed didn&#39;t take into account adding new records to the paginated collection.  As far as I can tell it doesn&#39;t anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with using code someone else has written is that sometimes you don&#39;t understand how it works.  I&#39;m okay with not understanding how a particular peice of code works in my project... as long as it doesn&#39;t cause problems.  Understanding every line of code you use, without a doubt, is a better way to code and makes you a better developer all around.  Sometimes you just have to get things done and hack it together however works.  I&#39;m thinking this isn&#39;t one of those situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Saturday night I decided to experiment with my own little &quot;development sprint&quot; to see how much I could get accomplished with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/asommer70/dvdpila&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD PIla!&lt;/a&gt; web app.  I was able to migrate the code from my self-hosted &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.gitlab.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Gitlab&lt;/a&gt; repo to Github, implement a HMLT5 video element in Ember, adjust the database schema for a field to container a URL for the video file, and a plethora of improvements to the Flask server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the sprint at 10:00pm on Saturday, and had the video element implemented by around 11:00 ish.  At which point I realized that I need to convert all my AVI files to MP4 so they can work in the video element, doh.  It&#39;s very cool to be able to view your videos in your a browser from any devise in your house, and I soon got caught up watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://duckduckgo.com/?q=terminator+salvation&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Terminator: Salvation&lt;/a&gt; which I haven&#39;t seen in a while.  So I got back to serious work on the project around 1:00am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 3:00am I had most of the server code fixed up, and all the small things working and looking good.  I went to bed at 3:00am meaning to get back up at 5:00am and continue working, but the snooze was just too good.  I ended up getting back into it at 5:30am after my son woke up.  There&#39;s not a better alarm clock in the world than a 16 month old child.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&#39;ve been on this pagination problem for about 4 hours now... hopefully I can have it locked up soon.  I think after that it&#39;ll be time to release a version 1.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 10:07:40 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/22/problems-with-pagination-and-ember/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/22/problems-with-pagination-and-ember/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Migrating Code and ConfigParser</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post-inner&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Discourse and PHP Woo&quot; src=&quot;http://www.thehoick.com/images/configparser.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve gotten around to migrating the actual code for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/asommer70/dvdpila&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;DVD Pila!&lt;/a&gt; web app.  It&#39;s now officiall more than just a Github pages &lt;a href=&quot;http://dvdpila.thehoick.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;webasite&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think from a design aspect it&#39;s my best work yet.  I&#39;ve really enjoyed sing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://refills.bourbon.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Refills&lt;/a&gt; mixin library as well as the other &lt;a href=&quot;http://bourbon.io/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Bourbon&lt;/a&gt; libraries.  Bourbon has become my goto design framework.  I still like Bootstrap and Foundation, but there&#39;s just something really cool about using straight Sass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing I accomplished today was to migrate the database connection code from using straight username, host, and password to storing those variables in a config file.  I never realized that Python came with great functions baked in like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.python.org/2/library/configparser.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;ConfigParser&lt;/a&gt; module.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In three quick lines your config files is read and your options are at your fingertips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;import ConfigParser

config = ConfigParser.ConfigParser()
config.readfp(open(&#39;config.cfg&#39;))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; along with the section to retrieve specefic values:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;python&quot;&gt;db_name = config.get(&#39;Database&#39;, &#39;db&#39;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course to write to a config file there is a &lt;em&gt;set&lt;/em&gt; method.  I think this will be a very useful thing to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party On!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[dvdpila]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 13:07:13 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/21/migrating-code-and-configparser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://dvdpila.thehoick.com//emberjs/2014/07/21/migrating-code-and-configparser/</guid>
        
        
        <category>emberjs</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
